# Jake Brawer

# PERSONAL DATA

Ph.D.: 3rd Year

Website: http://jakebrawer.com/ Email: jake.brawer@yale.edu

Github: https://github.com/JakeBrawer

#### RESEARCH OVERVIEW

Summary I build human-robot collaborative systems that learn through their interac-

tions with people. My research draws upon recent innovations in machine learning as well as foundational techniques in artificial intelligence for designing systems

that learn and reason in a transparent and robust way.

# **EDUCATION**

2016-Current Ph.D. in Computer Science

Yale University, Advisor: Brian Scassellati

2012-2016 B.A. in Cognitive Science; Computer Science minor

Vassar College

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2016-Current Robotics Ph.D. student -Social robotics laboratory, Yale University Human-

robot collaboration research under the supervision of Professor Brian Scassellati.

2014-2015 **Research Fellow** –Interdisciplinary robotics research lab, *Vassar College* Designed and programmed a genotype-phenotype mapping scheme for mobile behavior-

based robots incorporating sexual reproduction and ontogenetic factors.

2014 Neuroscience researcher – Icahn School of Medicine, *Mount Sinai* Conducted fMRI research on resting state networks in macaque monkeys. Acquired skills

using fMRI analysis software FSL.

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Spring 2018 Intelligent Robotics

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2017 Object Oriented Programming

Teaching Assistant

Fall 2014, Fall Perception and Action

2015

Teaching Assistant

#### TECHNICAL AND SCIENTIFIC SKILLS

Research Human-robot collaboration, natural language understanding

Programming Python (and scientific tools), C-C++, Rust, LATEX, Git, Jekyll, Emacs, Con-

tinuous integration (with Travis)

ML/AI General machine learning and computer vision techniques

Robots Robot operating system (ROS), 2+ years experience with Baxter research robot

System 4+ years of daily **Linux** experience

# GRANTS

March 2018 Bridging the Gap: An NSF Workshop on Conversational Agents and

Human–Robot Interaction

Justine Cassell, Brian Scassellati, Jake Brawer, Michael Madaio

NSF Cyber-Human Systems (CHS), Robust Intelligence, National Robotics Initia-

tive. Award #1829237

# SERVICE

 ${\bf Conference \quad International \ Conference \ on \ Humanoid \ Robots \ ({\bf Humanoids}; \ 2018)}$ 

reviews International Conference on Human–Robot Interaction (HRI; 2017)

Journal ACM Transactions on Human–Robot Interaction (THRI; 2019)

reviews

Students Acshi Haggenmiller (2016-2017) supervised Sarah Widder (2017-Current)

Tan Zong Xuan (2017-2018)

Kevin Choi (2018)

# CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Brawer, Jake, Olivier Mangin, Alessandro Roncone, Sarah Widder, and Brian Scassellati (2018). "Situated Human-Robot Collaboration: predicting intent from grounded natural language". In: *Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/IROS18.pdf.

Scassellati, Brian, Jake Brawer, Katherine Tsui, Setareh Nasihati Gilani, Melissa Malzkuhn, Barbara Manini, Adam Stone, Geo Kartheiser, Arcangelo Merla, Ari Shapiro, et al. (2018). "Teaching Language to Deaf Infants with a Robot and a Virtual Human". In: Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, p. 553. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/CHI18.pdf.

Tan, Zong Xuan, Jake Brawer, and Brian Scassellati (2018). "That's Mine! Learning Ownership Relations and Norms for Robots". In: Thirty-second AAAI conference on artificial intelligence. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/AAAI18.pdf.

#### JOURNAL ARTICLES

Brawer, Jake, Aaron Hill, Ken Livingston, Eric Aaron, Joshua Bongard, and John H Long Jr (2017). "Epigenetic Operators and the evolution of Physically embodied robots". In: Frontiers in Robotics and AI 4, p. 1. URL: https://jakebrawer.com/assets/pdfs/FRONTIERS17.pdf.